Hello and welcome to exercise number 72.
So we are asked to print the minimum and maximum nodes of the Circle Link and list both the video and
think about this algorithm, how we can implement a method that print the minimum, find the minimum
and print it and find the maximum and print it.
We need.
To concentrate on two things.
Searching for the link list and how we find the end of their circle of this and we have so many sources
about this topic and how to find the maximum, so we need to compare these elements with other elements.
So for that, I will go here and I will create a public static and it will return and void because just
a printing their printing friend Max.
And many minimum, it took Interferometer, the head node had its object of node.
And let's start making our algorithm.
First of all, check if the list list as empty as empty if had equal clocks and then return otherwise
pointer for traversing.
So we need a pointer to traverse, start searching, traversing
nodes, current
equal to had we put it, and point to the point that current to the hat we specify or we create in node
that is the same as had now.
Three Initialize
minimum and max values and minimum equal to integer the max value.
Max value and.
And Max, and we have seen this in the Matrix.
So in the arrays integer, the minimal right now, let's create a wide loop while loop currents.
This is the carrot that I have created as Geppetto.
So current.
The up next does not equal to have then this, while we're last note, is not reached.
So while note is not reached, last note is not reached, so we are traversing through all the notes.
If the current note is letters for them anymore, then replace it.
If current note is less than.
The minimum, then replace it.
How to do that, if current to date that less than minimum, then we can create minimum equal to care
and the date.
OK, now let's check for the maximum.
If current node is.
Greater than greater than.
Greater than them there, Max, replace it.
So if Gert and the data were greater than maximal, then replace it Max Max be equal to the current
DOT data.
Otherwise current equal to current dot.
Next, we need to move that current cursor to then next.
So while we and next does not equal to now, we need to move the cursor to the next one.
OK.
Now we need to print out the minimum and the max.
So print the minimum
minimum is equal to here.
It is equal to the minimum and maximum
maximum
equal to their max.
OK, let's test it by going to the main method and we call here.
Prince, maximum and minimum, we specified the head of this assault, and let's run.
And here we go, guys, we have two, three, one, six and five, the minimum between these numbers
and these notes is one, and the maximum is six.
So our algorithm is working fine and we have done this method that finds and prints out the minimum
and the maximum throughout searching the whole list for checking if it is the minimum and the maximum.
By the way, the time complexity of this method is oh of and because we are traversing through all the
the list to find the minimum and the max.